Guide to the James E. Babb Memorial Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
James E. Babb Memorial collection
1847-1942
MS 44
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1.5
(4 boxes, 1 folio)
A double collection of the papers of James Elisha Babb, a lawyer prominent in Idaho politics, and of his father-in-law, Charles Johnson Tinkham. Babb's correspondence, which was devoted largely to politics, included both local and nationally prominent figures. Among the most important were William E. Borah, with whom he corresponded from 1898 to 1933 on issues such as women's suffrage, the League of Nations and the Roosevelt Administration; and William Jennings Bryan, who wrote between 1880 and 1924. Of particular interest are Bryan's early letters explaining his reasons for entering politics and his letters in the 1920s defending fundamentalist Christianity. Charles Johnson Tinkham's papers are significant for his own Civil War letters and those from his fellow soldiers and officers in the Union Army. Included also in his papers are miscellaneous official documents relating to his war service and an autograph collection.
Babb, James E. (James Elisha), 1864-1934
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of James T. Babb, 1942-1968.
Arrangement
Arranged in two series: I. Correspondence. II. Writings and Memorabilia.
Scope and Contents
Series I, CORRESPONDENCE, holds five hundred and eighty-seven letters (1860-1942). Nearly five hundred of these letters were written to or by James Elisha Babb. The remaining letters were written to or by Babb's father-in-law, Charles Johnson Tinkham.
James Babb's correspondence deals primarily with state and national politics. His most prominent correspondents were Senator William E. Borah (one hundred and ninety-three items 1898-1933) and William Jennings Bryan (forty-five letters 1880-1924). Borah and Babb wrote each other about many national issues including women's suffrage, the League of Nations, the World Court, Roosevelt's National Recovery Act and the executive branch's influence over the judiciary. Borah also occasionally asked Babb to act as an intermediary between him and special interest groups in Idaho.
William Jennings Bryan also wrote to Babb about national politics. Babb and Bryan attended Illinois College together, and both had served on the college's debating team. Although Bryan was a Democrat and Babb was an equally staunch Republican, the Commoner insisted that their political views were not so different (1882). He also wrote candidly about his decision to move to Nebraska and enter politics (1889). Later, Bryan sent his friend a short note about his decision to resign as Secretary of State, and in 1919, he outlined his stand on the League of Nations. During the 1920's, Bryan drafted several letters defending fundamentalist Christianity against the onslaught of evolutionary thought (1923) and warned Babb to protect his son from agnostic professors at Yale.
Throughout his career Babb received letters from a variety of Idaho Republicans, including three governors, four senators, and numerous congressmen. All discuss the Republican party and politics in Idaho.
Babb's correspondence contains few family letters. The single letter from his wife, Daisey, concerns her observations of the 1892 Democratic National Convention. Through the influence of Bryan, she was allowed to attend the Democratic gathering in Chicago.
In addition to the correspondence of James E. Babb, this series contains eighty-nine letters to and from Charles Johnson Tinkham and his wife (1860-(1861-1862)-1891). Tinkham wrote fifty-three letters to his wife, Carrie, when he served as a Union officer in the Civil War. As a Lieutenant-Colonel in General Rosecrans' Army of the Mississippi Valley, Tinkham described the sights and sounds of army camp life, the movement of enemy troops, and the experiences of battle.
Tinkham was shot in the right hand in May 1862 while leading his troops into battle near Corinth, Mississippi. He convalesced for several months and then abruptly left the army. After reporting "a difficulty with Major Gillmore" over a military arrest he had made, Tinkham told his wife: "I could not have the matter arranged in a manner I considered satisfactory...(therefore) I tendered my resignation and had it accepted." The retired Lieutenant-Colonel returned to Homer, Illinois, and resumed work as a merchant.
The remaining letters in this series come from officers and enlisted men in the Union Army. Most wrote about the details of army life.
Series II, WRITINGS AND MEMORABILIA, contains over twenty-five documents pertaining to the Civil War. Most are written orders to Lieutenant-Colonel Charles Tinkham. This series also includes an autograph collection with twenty-one manuscripts signed by such diverse public figures as General Pierre DuPont (1821) and A1 Jolson (1921). Finally, this series holds eighteen folders of memorabilia including two photographs of William Jennings Bryan, genealogical records of local Idaho families, Mrs. Babb's scrapbook, two receipt books from the brokerage house of McAlister and Warren, and several folders of newspaper clippings about William E. Borah and his role in United States foreign policy.
The James E. Babb Papers were given to Yale University Library by James T. Babb. There were also donations to several other institutions: memorabilia of Daisy (Tinkham) Babb to St. Mary-of-the-Woods, Terre Haute, Ind. [now a college under a different name], where Mrs. Babb and her mother were educated; and diaries and memorabilia of James E. Babb to Illinois College, Jackson, Ill. [founded by one of the "Yale Bands"], and Union College of Law [now Northeastern University Law School].
Biographical / Historical
James Elisha Babb was born on 1864 January 11, the son of Milton and Elizabeth (Littler) Babb. Raised in Champaign County, Illinois, Babb attended Illinois College and graduated in 1882 with a B.S. In 1884 he received his law degree from Union College of Law, Northwestern University, and then entered private law practice in Chicago. Four years later he married Daisey Tinkham, the daughter of a Northern Civil War veteran, Charles Johnson Tinkham.
Babb moved to Lewiston, Idaho, in 1892 and soon became one of the most prominent lawyers and Republicans in the State. He was often asked to run for Justice of the State Supreme Court, Congressman, Senator, and Governor. Each time he turned down the requests. Nevertheless, he did play a prominent role in Idaho politics as close advisor to Senator William E. Borah and many other Republican office holders.
Babb died 1934 May 26.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Women -- Suffrage; Idaho -- Politics and government; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; United States -- Politics and government; West (U.S.); Autographs; Lawyers; Politicians; Argyll, George Douglas Campbell, Duke of, 1823-1900; Babb, James E. (James Elisha), 1864-1934; Banks, Nathaniel Prentiss, 1816-1894; Barnard, J. G. (John Gross), 1815-1882; Borah, William Edgar, 1865-1940; Bryan, William Jennings, 1860-1925; Cantor, Eddie, 1892-1964; Capen, Nahum, 1804-1886; Chafee, Adna Romanza, 1884-1941; Crawford, Samuel Wylie, 1827-1892; Dupont, Pierre, 1821-1870; Fergus, Robert Collyer; Franklin, William Buel, 1823-1903; Headley, J. T., 1813-1897; Heyburn, Weldon Brinton, 1852-1912; Jay, John, 1817-1894; Jolson, Al, 1886-1950; Lyon, Caleb, 1822-1875; McKinley, William, 1843-1901; Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945; Tinkham, Charles Johnson, 1825-1891; Wilson, Edgar, 1861-; League of Nations
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1860-1942; Series I; .75 linear feet (2 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  The correspondence of James Elisha Babb is arranged alphabetically by author.
  The correspondence of Charles Johnson Tinkham is divided into incoming and outgoing letters. Each is arranged alphabetically by author.
  - James E. Babb
    - Ailshie, James F., 1913-1914 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      General
      Letters To JEB/ From JEB: 2/0
    - American Law Institute, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Letters to JEB/From JEB: 1/0
    - Ames, James Barr, 1906, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Babb, Daisey T., 1892, 1897, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Letters To JEB/ From JEB: 1/2
    - Babb, James T., 1932 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Letters To JEB/ From JEB: 0/1
    - Baird, William Raimond, 1889 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Letters To JEB/ From JEB: 1/0
    - Bakewell, Charles W., 1923 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Baldridge, H. Clarence, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Beatty, H. James, 1896, 1906, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Letters To JEB/ From JEB: 8/0
    - Beveridge, Albert J., 1926 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Bobbs-Merrill Company, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Letters To JEB/ From JEB: 3/0
    - Borah, William E.
      - 1898, 1900, 1902, 1905, 1907, 1910, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 11)
        Letters To JEB/ From JEB: 9/1
      - 1913-1917 (Box 1, Folder 12)
        Letters To JEB/ From JEB: 12/13
      - 1918 (Box 1, Folder 13)
        Letters To JEB/ From JEB: 5/7
      - 1919 (Box 1, Folder 14)
        Letters To JEB/ From JEB: 3/9
      - 1920-1921 (Box 1, Folder 15)
        Letters To JEB/ From JEB: 12/7
      - 1922-1923 (Box 1, Folder 16)
        Letters To JEB/ From JEB: 1/6
      - 1924 (Box 1, Folder 17)
        Letters To JEB/ From JEB: 6/7
      - 1925-1926 (Box 1, Folder 18)
        Letters To JEB/ From JEB: 3/5
      - 1927 (Box 1, Folder 19)
        Letters To JEB/ From JEB: 5/15
      - 1928 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - 1929-1930 (Box 1, Folder 21)
        Letters To JEB/ From JEB: 4/9
      - 1931 (Box 1, Folder 22)
        Letters To JEB/ From JEB: 5/8
      - 1932-1933 (Box 1, Folder 23)
        Letters To JEB/ From JEB: 7/13
      - 1934 (Box 1, Folder 24)
        Letters To JEB/ From JEB: 2/6
    - Borchard, Edwin M., 1925 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Brady, James H., 1909, 1910, 1913 1914, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Bryan, Mary B., 1912-1915, 1925, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      Letters To JEB/ From JEB: 8/1
    - Bryan, William Jennings
      - 1880, 1882 (Box 1, Folder 28)
        Letters To JEB/ From JEB: 4/0
      - 1888-1990, 1892, 1894, 1896 (Box 1, Folder 29)
        Letters To JEB/ From JEB: 9/0
      - 1897, 1900, 1904, 1906, 1907, 1909, 1913, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 30)
        Letters To JEB/ From JEB: 14/0
      - 1917, 1919-1920 (Box 1, Folder 31)
        Letters To JEB/ From JEB: 5/3
      - 1922-1924 (Box 1, Folder 32)
        Letters To JEB/ From JEB: 5/4
    - Budge, Alfred, 1918, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Bunn, Charles W., 1902 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Burr, Stiles W., 1915 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Cage, Milton G., 1901, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Carnegie Public Library, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Cavanan, Charles C., 1916 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Cobb, Calvin, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Coffin, Frank R., undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Daily Statesman, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Dale, E. E., 1925 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Davis, D. W., 1920 (Box 1, Folder 37)
      Letters To JEB/ From JEB: 1/1
    - Davis, E. G., 1920 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Dyer, Charles E., 1886 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Dunbar, Charles E., Jr., 1933 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Eaton, Amasa M., 1906 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Elliott, Howard, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Elliott, Thompson C., 1931, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Fess, Simeon D., 1920 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Fergus, Robert C., 1924, 1931-1932 (Box 1, Folder 42)
      Letters To JEB/ From JEB: 6/3
    - Foss, George E., 1901, undated (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - French, Burton L., 1924 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Fry, George C., 1911 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Gibson, Will H., 1920 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Good, James W., 1920 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Gooding, Frank R., 1902, 1918, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 45)
      Letters To JEB/ From JEB: 3/1
    - Haines, John M., 1912-1914 (Box 1, Folder 46)
      Letters To JEB/ From JEB: 5/0
    - Hamer, Thomas R., 1909 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Hanly, J. Frank, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Hendrick, A. W., 1914 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Heyburn, Weldon B., 1898, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Idaho League of Borah Voters, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Johnson, Hiram, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Johnson, O. C., 1934 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Kitchell, J. W., 1931 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Lee, E. William, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Lodge, Henry C., 1920 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Lodge, John D., 1924 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Lowden, Frank C., 1893 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - McConnell, William J., 1896-1897, 1918, 1920 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - McCutcheon, John T., 1927 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - McKinley, William, 1896 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Martzen, Felix, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Meuli, Martin, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Mills, Ogden L., 1920 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Milton, George F.
      - 1931 April - September (Box 2, Folder 53)
        Letters To JEB/ From JEB: 10/7
      - 1931 October - 1932 March (Box 2, Folder 54)
        Letters To JEB/ From JEB: 3/8
      - 1932 May - 1934 April (Box 2, Folder 55)
        Letters To JEB/ From JEB: 8/10
    - Morgan, William M., 1918 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - The Oregonian, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Poindexter, Miles, 1919-1920 (Box 2, Folder 57)
      Letters To JEB/ From JEB: 8/2
    - Ramnelkamp, Charles H., 1916 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Rockwell, Irvin E., 1919 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Shoup, George L., 1900 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Smith, Addison T., 1916, 1920, 1922, 1924, 1925, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 59)
      Letters To JEB/ From JEB: 4/3
    - Spencer, Herbert R., 1930 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Sullivan, Isaac N., 1905, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Strahan, James A., 1928 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Walker, George R., 1932 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Watkins, William W., 1892 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - White, Fred, 1902 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Wigmore, John H., 1920 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Wilson, Edgar, 1895, (1896), 1900 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Wilson, Lester S., 1902 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Woodward and Palmer, 1898 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Unidentified, 1893 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Incoming correspondence
      - Babb, Daisey T., 1892-1942, undated (Box 2, Folder 65)
      - Borah, William E., to James T. Babb., 1927, 1934, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 66)
      - French, Burton L., to James T. Babb, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 66)
      - Owen, Ruth B., to James T. Babb, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 66)
      - Incoming correspondence to others, 1869, 1882, 1913, 1918-1919, 1927, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 67)
      - Littler, Elisha
        - to Elizabeth Babb, 1863 January (Box 2, Folder 68)
        - to Milton Babb, 1863 (Box 2, Folder 69)
      - Babb, James P., to Milton Babb, 1855 May 30 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Charles J. Tinkham
    - Coffeen, M. D., 1861 September 6, October 18 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Fuller, Allen C., 1862 April 10 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Rosecrans, General ____, 1862 August (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Loomis, John M., 1862 January 7 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Tinkham, ____, 1862 June 8 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Tinkham, Carrie J. (Box 2, Folder 71)
      - 1861 Jan, August - September (Box 2, Folder 72)
      - 1861 October 12-18 (Box 2, Folder 73)
      - 1861 October 23 - 1867 October 27 (Box 2, Folder 74)
      - 1861 November (Box 2, Folder 75)
      - 1861 December (Box 2, Folder 76)
      - 1862 February - March (Box 2, Folder 77)
      - 1862 April (Box 2, Folder 78)
      - 1862 May (Box 2, Folder 79)
      - 1862 June (Box 2, Folder 80)
      - 1862 Sep, Dec, undated (Box 2, Folder 81)
    - Brooking, C. H., 1862 March (Box 2, Folder 82)
    - Coffeen, M. D., 1862 June (Box 2, Folder 83)
    - DeForrest, E. C., 1860 November 24 (Box 2, Folder 84)
    - DeGraff, T., n.y. June 27 (Box 2, Folder 85)
    - Folks, J. H., 1862 February 6 (Box 2, Folder 86)
    - Kelley, John., 1862 July (Box 2, Folder 87)
    - Loomis, John M., 1862 January - Mar, 1890 October - 1891 January (Box 2, Folder 88)
    - Moore, W., 1862 August 28 (Box 2, Folder 89)
    - Salisbury, Robert, undated (Box 2, Folder 90)
    - Siller, A., 1862 October 25 (Box 2, Folder 91)
    - Skinner, John W., 1863 Jan, June (Box 2, Folder 92)
    - Smith, Charles, 1861 October 29 (Box 2, Folder 93)
    - Wilds, R. F., 1862 January (Box 2, Folder 94)
    - Younker, S. T., 1861 August (Box 2, Folder 95)
    - Incoming Correspondence
      - Folks, John W., to Carrie J. Tinkham, 1862 May (Box 2, Folder 96)
      - Kelley, John W., to Carrie J. Tinkham, 1861 Oct, 1862 May (Box 2, Folder 97)
      - Northrop, J., to Carrie J. Tinkham, 1891 October 26 (Box 2, Folder 98)
      - Incoming correspondence to others, 1862 Apr, June - July (Box 2, Folder 99)
- WRITINGS AND MEMORABILIA, 1735-(1861-1923)-1940; Series II; .75 linear feet (2 boxes)
  Civil War Documents is arranged chronologically.
  Autographs is arranged chronologically.
  Memorabilia is arranged chronologically.
  - Civil War Documents
    - Invoices, 1861, undated (Box 3, Folder 100)
    - General Order, No. 4, 1862 March 17 (Box 3, Folder 101)
    - General Order, No. 20, by General Stanley, 1862 April 30 (Box 3, Folder 102)
    - Document giving Charles Tinkham the Power of Attorney for John Gebink, 1862 April (Box 3, Folder 103)
    - Special Order, No. 28, by General Stanley, 1862 June 10 (Box 3, Folder 104)
    - Special Field Orders, No. 134, by Major-General Halleck, 1862 June 29 (Box 3, Folder 105)
    - General Order, No. 94, by General Rosecrans, 1862 July 14 (Box 3, Folder 106)
    - Order by Brigadier General W. L. Elliott, 1862 July 19 (Box 3, Folder 107)
    - Special Order, No. 185, by General Rosecrans, 1862 July 19 (Box 3, Folder 108)
    - "Names of officers detached for recruiting,", 1862 July (Box 3, Folder 109)
    - General Order, No. 1116, by General Rosecrans, 1862 August 11 (Box 3, Folder 110)
    - General Order, No. 57, by General Stanley, 1862 August 13 (Box 3, Folder 111)
    - Orders by Colonel R. Murphy, 1862 September 4, September 8 (Box 3, Folder 112-113)
    - Special Order, No. 62, by General Stanley, 1862 September 10 (Box 3, Folder 114)
    - Order by General Stanley, 1862 September 11 (Box 3, Folder 115)
    - Miscellaneous Orders, 1862 (Box 3, Folder 116)
    - Pension certificate, 1864 September (Box 3, Folder 117)
    - Account of property taken from Peter and Martha Babb during the Civil War, 1865 June 13 (Box 3, Folder 118)
    - Proceedings of the 16th and 17th Annual Reunions of the 26th Illinois Veteran Volunteer Infantry, 1900 August 29 (Box 3, Folder 119)
    - Invitation to the l5th Annual Reunion of the 26th Illinois Veteran Volunteer Infantry, 1899 October 18 (Box 3, Folder 119)
    - List of Officers in the 26th Illinois Volunteers (Box 3, Folder 120)
    - Speech to the soldiers of the 26th Illinois Volunteers, undated (Box 3, Folder 121)
    - "A Recruit's First Battle," by L. R. Thompson, undated (Box 3, Folder 122)
    - petition addressed to Col. John Mason Loomis, 1861 November 30 (Box 5)
    - Charles Tinkham's commission as captain, 1862 July 25 (Box 5)
  - Autographs
    - Land deed, 1735 (Box 3, Folder 123)
    - Transference of a bond signed by P. Coffin, 1798 March 20 (Box 3, Folder 124)
    - Receipt for shoeing of horses, Ezra Woodin, 1800 June 2 (Box 3, Folder 125)
    - General Pierre DuPont, request for an interview, 1821 (?) (Box 3, Folder 126)
    - Letter: Lyon, Caleb, to J. K. Paulding, 1840 February 7 (Box 3, Folder 127)
    - Letter: Butler, Benjamin, to "Messrs.,", 1854 April 7 (Box 3, Folder 128)
    - Letter: Banks, Nathaniel P., to Moses Kimball, 1860 August 15 (Box 3, Folder 129)
    - Application for re-appointment to the Idaho Supreme Court by Milton Kelley, 1870 January 4 (Box 3, Folder 130)
    - Letter: Barnard, General John G., to J. Hilgard, 1870 May 26 (Box 3, Folder 131)
    - Letter: Headley, Joel Tyler, to "Sir,", 1872 September 18 (Box 3, Folder 132)
    - Petition to President Ulysses S. Grant signed by James Wilson, 1873 March 5 (Box 3, Folder 133)
    - Letter: Capen, Nahum, to R. S. Spofford, 1875 December 19 (Box 3, Folder 134)
    - Letters: Jay, John
      - to Governor Seymour, 1884 December 13 (Box 3, Folder 135)
      - to the Editor of The Independent, 1888 February 26 (Box 3, Folder 135)
    - Letter: George Douglas Campbell, 8th Duke of Argyll, 1885 February 11 (Box 3, Folder 136)
    - Letter: Franklin, William B., to Mrs. Black, 1885 July 21 (Box 3, Folder 137)
    - Letter: Crawford, S. W., to Emily W. Peck, 1886 June 24 (Box 3, Folder 138)
    - Letter: Chafee, Adna Romanza, to William H. Ward, 1904 March 8 (Box 3, Folder 139)
    - Letter: Jolson, Al, to "Alderman,", 1921 August 12 (Box 3, Folder 140)
    - Letter: Cantor, Eddie, to Mr. Alderman, 1924 February 9 (Box 3, Folder 141)
    - List of signatures of the Home Guards of Homer, Illinois, undated (Box 3, Folder 142)
  - Memorabilia
    - Photographs
      - William Jennings Bryan, 1881, 1897 (Box 3, Folder 143)
      - John Mason Loomis, undated (Box 3, Folder 143)
      - Hardward and implement store owned by Charles Johnston Tinkham and Michael Coffeen Tinkham, Undated (Box 3, Folder 143 A)
      - Interior of Edward Treat Mudge in Homer Illinois, 1847 (Box 3, Folder 143 B)
    - Receipt books for the brokerage house, McAlister and Warren, 1883 January - 1888 December (Box 3, Folder 144-145)
    - Two envelopes, 1890, 1891 (Box 3, Folder 146)
    - Business card of Charles J. Tinkham
    - Scrapbook compiled by Daisey Tinkham Babb, 1898 September 30 (Box 4, Folder 147)
    - Certificates of James E. Babb, 1909, 1911, 1913 (Box 4, Folder 148)
    - Speech: fragment from an Address by William E. Borah, 1918 February 5 (Box 4, Folder 149)
    - Letter to the Editor by James E. Babb, 1919 October 11 (Box 4, Folder 150)
    - Documents and notes concerning the erection of the Spaulding Missionary Memorial, 1920-1924 (Box 4, Folder 151)
    - Photographs of the Spaulding Missionary Memorial (Box 4, Folder 152)
    - Newspaper clippings (Box 4, Folder 153)
    - Essay: "Doctor Marcus Whitman, 1842-1843," by Margaret E. Babb, 1922 June 10 (Box 4, Folder 154)
    - The Commoner, 1923 January (Box 4, Folder 155)
    - Speech: "Science vs. Evolution," by William Jennings Bryan, 1923 April 13 (Box 4, Folder 156)
    - Prayer: "Thanksgiving," by Mrs. Bryan, undated (Box 4, Folder 156)
    - Speech: On the history of Idaho, by C. E. Arney, 1940 June 7 (Box 4, Folder 157)
    - "Northwest Cities and Towns - Origins of Names" (Box 4, Folder 158)
    - Geneology and notes on the Hart Family (Box 4, Folder 159)
    - Notes on the lineage of Alice Whitman (Box 4, Folder 160)